A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia 1925-1930
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia 1925-1930
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.472 VIII
This collection consists of 1,500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence and related papers of President Edwin Anderson Alderman originally kept in the President's office and maintained in a separate file labelled "Personal."
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Personal Files 1925-1930
  - "A"--Alderman Family 1925-1930 (Box 1)
  - Alderman's 25th Anniversary 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    Furniture and silver to be given to the Aldermans
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    Alderman's election to membership
  - "B" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    Balz, A. G. A.; Battle, George Gordon; Bridges, Robert of Scribner's Magazine; Bruce, Philip A.; Bryan, John Stewart; Butler, Nicholas Murray; Byrd Harry F.
  - "C" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    Century Association; Chase, H. W.; Crane, Charles R.; Curtiss, Harry
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    Dabney, Charles William; Denny, George H., President of University of Alabama
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    Early, Sen. N. B.; Eliot, Charles W.; Eliot, Samuel A.; Erikson, A. W.
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    Faison, Henry E., speech on Wilmington Presbytery; Flexner, A. F., General Education Fund; Flinner, Ira A.; Northwood School; Freeman, Douglas S.; Fuller, Thomas Staples re: Dobie as Dean of Law School
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 2)
    Glass, Carter; Glazebrook, Otis, former chaplain of the University; Gordon, Armistead C.; Graves, Louis; Graves, Ralph re: ex-Senator John S. Williams; Grayson, Cary T., re: publication of Woodrow Wilson letters
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 2)
    Harper and Brothers, re: "The Closed Garden" by Julien Green; Henderson, Archibald
  - Hall of Fame Nominations 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - Institutes--Institute for Government Research 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - Institute--Institute of Economics 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - Institutes--Institution of Politics, Williamstown 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 2)
    Jarman, J. L.; Jefferson, Thomas
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 2)
    Kimball, Fiske
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 2)
    Laird, W. W.; Latane, J. H.; Lawrence, Sir Walter; Lewis, Dr. Ivey F.; Lewis, Mrs. Ivey; Lindsay, James H.; Long, A. W.; Longwell, Daniel; Lusk, W. B.
  - Lake Placid Club 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - Library of Southern Literature 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - "M" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 2)
    McAdoo, William G.
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 2)
    National Institute of Arts and Letters; Noble, M. C. S. of University of North Carolina
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 2)
    O' Connor, Betty P.; Odenheimer, S.; Odum, Howard W.; Oldham, Edward A.; Ortman, R. O.
  - "P" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 3)
    Page, Mrs. Walter re: publication of volume of Walter Page's letters; Patton, John S.; Peabody, George Foster; Phi Beta Kappa; Pitt, R. H. re: religion at the University
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 3)
    Robinson, Joseph T.; Roosevelt, Archibald B.; Ryan, Thomas Fortune
  - "S" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 3)
    Sandridge, Edward, re: Alderman as a possible candidate for Governor; Scott, Frederic W.; Sketches on Alderman; Stires, Bishop Ernest M.; Swanson, Claude A.
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 3)
    Tittle, Walter; Tucker, Beverley
  - "W" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 2 folders (Box 3)
    Williams, John Sharp
  - West Papers 1925-1930 (Box 3)
  - Wilson, Woodrow 1925-1930 (Box 3)
  - "Y" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 3)
    Yochum, Ms. Mary C.; Young, Dr. Hugh H.
  - "Z" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 3)
    Zimmer, Samuel W.